Edward R. Murrow Papers MS025
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Awards, 1938 -- 1972; MS025.010; 4.15 Linear Feet; 21 Audiovisual Object(s)
  - Needlepoint vest in fame, MS025.010.012.00009 (Box 12)
    Dimensions: 3 1/4"H x 4 3/4"W. Made by Peggy Wood. Gold frame with two sections for photos. One side has paper with hand written message (barely readable) and other side had black embroidered vest. The hand written message says "Near New Year's Eve and a person said to a person 'make me a needlepoint vest' like Will's." Original collections documentation note: "see p-to-p program, 12/34/54."
    Needleworking
  - Gift to Edward R. Murrow from Sin Korea, December 25, 1952; MS025.010.013.00001 (Box 13)
    Dimensions: 4 1/2" Diameter x 3 1/2"H. Small round metal plate with stand for circular fan like structure. Marked with tag.
    Commemoratives
  - Brown, green, and baize bird, MS025.010.013.00002 (Box 13)
    Dimensions: 8"H x 2 1/2"W. Bird made of natural materials. Damaged during construction project in the ERM Room in summer, 2010. There are tears in the leather cover of right leg and feet.
    Birds
  - Assembly of Captive European Nations recognition of Edward R. Murrow, 1965-07-21; MS025.010.014.00001 (Box 14)
    Dimensions: 8"L x 17"W x 16"H. Wooden stand with brass plaque and 9 flags from each captive nation. Reads: "To Edward R. Murrow trail-blazing reporter and commentator eloquent champion of truth foe of tyranny. In posthumous recognition of his proven concern for the communist-enslaved nations of east-central europe and his consistent support of their freedom goal. Assembly of Captive European Nations. Washington, July 21, 1965." Maker: International Bronze Tablet Company,
    NY, NY. Piece of paper underneath stand with flag identification.
    Awards; Flags
  - Academy of Radio and Television Arts and Sciences, Michael Award, 1952; MS025.010.015.00001 (Box 15)
    Dimensions: 4"L x 6 1/4"H x 2"W. Gold trophy with man holding branches. Award for Best News Program in Radio.
  - Member of United Air Lines 100,000 Mile Club Plaque, MS025.010.015.00002 (Box 15)
    Dimensions: 6 1/2" W x 8 1/2" H. Wood plaque with bronze plate and image of an airplane and globe. Reads: "In appreciation of your valuable contribution to air transport progress"
  - 21 Club sculpture, MS025.010.016.00001 (Box 16)
    Dimensions: 9 1/2"L x 7"H x 4 1/2"W. Metal object/sculpture. Pair of doors with number 21 on front of object.
  - Distinguished Service Award from Association of Founders and Friends of Roosevelt College, May 26, 1954; MS025.010.016.00002 (Box 16)
    Dimensions: 9 1/2"H x 3 1/4"W x 3 1/4" L. Bronze head of Franklin Roosevelt on square stone base for distinguished service to the principles of democracy. Head a little bit loose from base.
    Awards; Roosevelt College
  - American College of Radio Arts Crafts and Sciences Fellow in Radio Hall of Fame, 1962; MS025.010.017.00001 (Box 17)
    Dimensions: 13 1/2"H x 11 3/4"W. Gold wooden frame, red velvet matt surrounding medallion and engraved plate with award specifics. Generally good condition. Frame scratched in several places and paper backing torn and warped.
    Awards; American College of Radio Arts
  - Robert E. Sherwood Award, 1959; MS025.010.017.00002 (Box 17)
    Dimensions: 11 1/4"H x 15 1/4"W. Wood plaque with silver plate attached. Award presented by The Fund for the Republic and given to CBS-TV for "Small World," for contributing to the "understanding of freedom and justice." Crack in bottom right corner on front. Silver plate removed from wooden plaque when removed from ERM Room Exhibit, spring 2010
  - The John F. Kennedy Lodge B'Nai B'Rith "Profiles in Courage" Award, Mar. 29, 1965; MS025.010.018.00001 (Box 18)
    Dimensions: 17"H x 14"W. Wood plaque with bronze inscription, image of JFK. Maker: American Trophies, Washington D.C.
  - Jewish War Veterans of the U.S. Award, Citizen of the Year, 1956-1957, 1957-08-16; MS025.010.019.00001 (Box 19)
    Dimensions: 18"H x 13 1/2"W. Wooden plaque with decorative certificate. Awarded on Aug. 16, 1957 by William Carmen, National Commander.
  - The Billboard Award, Best Network Commentator, 1956-1957, MS025.010.019.00002 (Box 19)
    Dimensions: 17"H x 14"W. Wood plaque with color award for outstanding achievement in television programming during 1956-1957 season, at the TV Industry's Annual Program and Talent Awards. Maker: Lifetime Process Studios, New York, NY.
  - Eisenhower Exchange Fellowships, Inc. certificate, October 14, 1953-10-14; MS025.010.020.00001 (Box 20)
    Dimensions: 23"H x 17"W. Certificate in black and gold wood frame.
  - Clipper Club Pan American World Airways Membership Certificate, July 14 1958, 1958-07-14; MS025.010.021.00001 (Box 21)
    Dimensions: 13.25"H x 16.25"L In a wooden frame with beige matting. Reads: This is to certify that Edward R. Murrow having made valuable contributions to the advancement and public acceptance of air transportation, is hereby enrolled as a member in good standing of the Clipper Club. It is signed by Juan Trippe, president of the Pan American World Airways The System of the Flying Clippers
  - Honored and Outstanding Citizen of Baltimore Award, February 2, 1957-02-02; MS025.010.021.00002 (Box 21)
    Dimensions: 11"H x 14"L In a black frame. Signed by Leon Abramson, the Acting Mayor of the City of Baltimore.
  - Royal Society of the Knights of Carrousel at Charlotte, North Carolina Certificate, November 21, 1956; MS025.010.022.00001 (Box 22)
    Dimensions: 15.5" H x 17.5"L Framed in black with gold trim, and white mat board with gold trim. Stamped with the signum of the Royal Society of the Knights of Carrousel. Edward R. Murrow is awarded and dubbed a Duke of the Royal Society of the Knights of Carrousel
  - Drexel Institute of Technology Annual Business Administration Award, Apr. 1955, MS025.010.023.00001 (Box Large Map Case 2 Drawer 9)
    Dimensions: 18 3/4"H x 12 3/4"W. Certificate in black frame. Awarded by the College of Business Administration.Deframed after moved to stacks from exhibit room, spring 2011.
  - Doctor of Laws, Muhlenberg College, June, 1947; MS025.010.023.00002 (Box Large Map Case 2 Drawer 9)
    Dimensions: 18.75"H x 14.75"L. In a black frame with white matting. The diploma is in Latin.Deframed after moved to stacks from exhibit room, spring 2011
  - Federal Bar Association Dedication Day Award, 1963-09-26; MS025.010.024.00001 (Box 24)
    Dimensions: 15"W x 12"L. Solid wood plaque with engraved metal plate. Award from Philadelphia chapter of the FBA. Two noticeable scratches by signature of Philadelphia mayor. Hook on back. Maker: Devitt Trophies, 727 Walnut St., Philadelphia, PA.
    Awards; Federal Bar Association
  - Freedoms Foundation Award, 1955; MS025.010.024.00002 (Box 24)
    Dimensions: 10.5"H x 13.5"W. Black and white poster "For The United States Army Reserve's Powerful Documentary Film, 'The Whites of Their Eyes'," written by Lee Rogow and narrated by E.R. Murrow.
    Awards; Poster; Freedoms Foundation
  - Hamilton College Diploma, 1954; MS025.010.024.00003 (Box Shared 132)
    Dimensions: 15 3/4"H x 19 1/2"W. Black and white diploma in black wooden frame. Hanging wire on back.
  - Doctor of Journalism degree from Temple University, 1950; MS025.010.024.00004 (Box Shared 132)
    This date is approximate. Dimensions: 17 1/4"H x 22"W. Black and white diploma with gold school seal. Paper warped.
    Diplomas; Temple University
- Additional accessions, MS025.011; 1 Volumes
  - Late Murrow material, MS025-007 (Box data_value_missing_e433e7be9b4d85ea289de84f60c6e308, Box 1)
    This item was found uncatalogued in the stacks. former barcode 39090015515717g
  - Late Murrow material, MS025-008 (Box data_value_missing_e433e7be9b4d85ea289de84f60c6e308, Box 2)
    Found uncataloged in stacks; former barcode 39090015515725g
  - Digitized files of News reel, June 6 1944-January 19, 1945 radio broadcasts, MS025-009 (Box data_value_missing_e433e7be9b4d85ea289de84f60c6e308, Box 3)
    digital copy of MS 25/005.011.239. Digitized by WGBH 2008. former barcode 39090015515733g
  - 2 oversize BBC records, MS025-010 (Box data_value_missing_05b4da3e50d85afd11acbf4f59fb3aa8)
    STORED IN YELLOW OVERSIZE BOX. Found uncataloged in stacks 2006.
  - Kyle Goode donation of Murrow script, MS025-011 (Box data_value_missing_2f9562bc2d7beebaa8efbe4242f7c195, Box 4)
    Former barcode 39090015515766g
  - Murrow poster, MS025-012 (Box data_value_missing_9a87feb707f125aa3bd1ee64b355488f, Box 5)
    See also Leland Stowe MS129 former barcode 39090011520547g